<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
 *
 * Overview dataINT
 * Copyright (c) 2019 - Hani A. Ibrahim
 *
-->
<refentry xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:scilab="http://www.scilab.org" xml:lang="en_US" xml:id="dataint_overview">
	<refnamediv>
		<refname>Overview</refname>
		<refpurpose>An overview of the dataINT toolbox.</refpurpose>
	</refnamediv>
	<refsection>
		<title>Introduction and Purpose</title>
		<para>
        This toolbox provides functions for importing and exporting tabular data. It is based on Scilab's in-built functions csvRead(), xlsRead(), and cvsWrite(). The purpose of this toolbox is to make the use of these functions more convenient by introducing a GUI for selecting the files and specifying the im- or export parameters. It can easily integrated in scripts and controlled by dataINT's exit codes but also used in Scilab's console for importing or exporting data conveniently.
    </para>
	<para>
        dataINT's import functions read the data from a comma-separated value (*.csv), other text-based data (*.dat, *.txt) or from a binary Excel 95-2003 file (*.xls) into a Scilab matrix variable for further processing. The export function saves a Scilab matrix into a comma-separated value (*.csv) or other text-based file( *.dat, *.txt). The field separators of the CSV files can be comma, semicolon, tabular or space. The decimal separator can be point or comma. This makes dataINT flexible to a huge variety of text-based data formats. 
    </para>
	<para>
		<note>
			<para>
		dataINT can handle numerical (doubles) data only. Strings are represented as NaN (%nan).
	</para>
		</note>
		</para>
		<para>
		<note>
			<para>
		dataINT cannot import XML-based Excel files (Excel 2007 and higher)!
	</para>
		</note>
		</para>
	</refsection>
	<refsection>
		<title>Functions</title>
		<variablelist>
			<varlistentry>
				<term><link linkend="DI_readcsv">DI_readcsv</link>:</term>
				<listitem>
					<para> Read data from a comma-separated-value (*.csv) or another text-based data file (*.dat, *.txt) and store it into a matrix variable interactively.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term><link linkend="DI_readxls">DI_readxls</link>:</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Read data from a binary Excel 95-2003 file and store it into a matrix variable interactively.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term><link linkend="DI_writecsv">DI_writecsv</link>:</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Write a Scilab matrix of doubles to a comma-separated value or other text-based file interactively.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
		<para>Type "demo_gui()" in Scilab's console and search for "dataINT" to get started.</para>
	</refsection>
	<refsection>
		<title>Authors</title>
		<para>
		Hani A. Ibrahim - hani.ibrahim@gmx.de
	</para>
	</refsection>
</refentry>
